Hi, my name is Emily Yueh and I'm a partner
in the New York office of McKinsey,
a global leader within the healthcare
and advanced industry sectors.
Over the last ten-plus years, I've loved serving our clients
across a range of super interesting and complex challenges,
ranging from strategy to organization
to transformations.
I'm thrilled to be here with you today
and delighted to be part of your core faculty.
So my name is Mark Matakis. I'm incredibly excited
to join Emily in this course on problem solving.
I've been with McKinsey for over ten years.
I spend a lot of my time on capability building,
particularly in the leadership and management space.
But problem solving is one of the things I'm really passionate about.
I love the way taking a very structured approach enables us
to take a very ambiguous or complex problem
and actually drive to an actionable insight.
Problem solving is something that Emily and I both really enjoy,
and we're excited in this course to talk about what problem solving is.
Throughout this course, you'll be learning from the two of us,
as well as some of our colleagues, alumni and business leaders.
Problem solving is something that we're all doing
constantly in our day-to-day work.
And hopefully in the course of these next few hours,
you're going to learn a couple of techniques and tools
to really take more deliberate choices
about how you go about problem solving.
And what's interesting is that problem solving,
when done well, is not only more efficient
and more practical — it actually gets you
to a better answer and a better outcome.
And so ultimately, I think a good place for us to start
is to ask: what actually is problem solving? Mark?
I think the question of what is problem solving
is one that we hear a lot.
I like to think of problem solving as the process by which
we make decisions, either for ourselves or with our teams.
And ultimately, it's something we do every day.
In some cases, it involves a very long-term project.
It could be over many weeks or many months.
But in some cases, it's really problem solving in the moment.
You're in a meeting, someone asks a question, and you need to decide:
how am I going to figure this out,
and what am I going to do?
I think, for me, problem solving is both an art and a science,
and we're going to learn some techniques
around how we can take a very structured approach to that —
but a lot of it is in the application and the day-to-day.
But there's another question that I hear a lot, which is:
what makes a good problem solver? I'd love to hear your perspective.
I think great problem solving, to me,
really is incredibly structured.
And structured can mean a bunch of different things. It can mean
that you have a deliberate approach to how you break apart the problem.
I think structure can also mean being very thoughtful
about what you're going to tackle and what you're not going to tackle.
In other words, being really 80/20: what's the 20%
that's going to drive 80% of the value you're actually going to see?
And then the third piece, to me, is really thinking
about how you're going to actually implement it.
And that's oftentimes a critical piece of problem solving
that's misstepped or overlooked.
So you need to be really thoughtful about: who are the stakeholders?
How are you going to roll this out? What is realistic?
What are some of the common pitfalls?
So being very structured, end to end,
is one of the core tenets
of being a good problem solver.